Guide to the Marty Rosenbluth papers, 1980-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marty Rosenbluth papers 1980-2005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Rosenbluth, Marty.
12 linear feet Extent: 12,000 Items
Marty Rosenbluth was Amnesty International's area specialist for Israel/Occupied Territories in the 1980's. He is also an independent documentary film-maker. The Marty Rosenbluth papers include publications, reports, case studies, press-releases, mailings, communications, leaflets, videocassettes, DVD's, and ephemera created by Palestinian and Israeli human rights groups.
RL.01123
Language: Material in English, Arabic, Hebrew
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Marty Rosenbluth papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 12/20/06.
Biographical Note
Marty Rosenbluth was Amnesty International's area specialist for Israel/Occupied Territories in the 1980's. He is also an independent documentary film-maker.
Collection Overview
The Marty Rosenbluth papers include publications, reports, case studies, press-releases, mailings, communications, leaflets, videocassettes, DVD's, and ephemera created by Palestinian and Israeli human rights groups. These groups include Al-Haq (Law in the Service of Man), Badil, B’Tselem, Hamoked (Center for the Defense of the Individual), Public Committee Against Torture in Israel, The West Bank Data Base Project, and Alternative Information Center. The papers also feature materials from Palestinian trade unions and United States-based solidarity groups, as well as unofficial, locally published first-person reports of events and conditions in the Occupied Territories.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Rosenbluth, Marty; Law in the Service of Man (Organization: Ram Allah); Hamoked Center for the Defense of the Individual (Jerusalem); Be-tselem (Organization: Jerusalem); West Bank Data Base Project; Moked la-haganat ha-perat (Jerusalem); Human rights -- Middle East; Human rights -- Israel; Human rights -- Palestine; Human rights -- Gaza Strip; Human rights -- West Bank; Human rights advocacy; Human rights workers; Human Rights Archive (Duke University)
Contents of Collection
- B'Tselem, 1990-2005
  - Printed material, 1990-2005, (1-7 of 11 folders) (Box 1)
  - Printed material, 1990-2005, (8-11 of 11 folders) (Box 2)
  - Human rights reports, 1994-2004
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1995-2005, (3 folders)
- Palestine Human Rights Organizations, 1983-2003
  - Adalah the Legal Center for Arab Minority Rights in Israel, 1998-2002 (Box 3)
  - Badil, 2000-2001, (2 folders)
  - Birzeit University, 1983-1989
  - Gaza Community Mental Health Programme, 1993-1994
  - International Center for Peace in the Middle East, 1983,1985, (2 folders)
  - The Jerusalem Media and Communication Centre, 1989-1996
  - LAW- the Palestine Society for the Protection of Human Rights and the Environment, 1997,1999
  - Palestine Human Rights Information Center, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - Palestine human rights, miscellaneous publications, 1985-2003, (2 folders)
  - Palestine human rights, publications by individuals, 1989
  - Palestine human rights, academic journals, 1995
  - Palestine human rights, miscellaneous communications, 1984-1997 and undated
  - The Palestinian Human Rights Monitoring Group, 1998
  - Public Committee Against Torture in Israel, 1999-2002, (2 folders)
- Al-Haq, 1980-2003
  - Printed material, 1980-2003, (7 folders) (Box 5)
  - "Human Rights Focus", 1991-1992
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1994,2003, and undated (Box 6)
  - Newsletters, press releases, 1984-1988, and undated, (2 folders)
- Hamoked, 1997-2006
  - Printed material, 1997-2006, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Annual report, 2000
- West Bank Data Project, 1983-1990
  - Printed material, 1983-1990, (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Alternative Information Center, 1986-1998
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1988,1994,1997 (Box 7)
  - "New from Within", 1986-1998, (3 folders)
  - "The Other Front", 1988-1992
- Foreign and US-based Solidarity Groups, 1974-2003
  - Center for Policy Analysis on Palestine, 1994-1997 (Box 7)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1988,1996
  - Middle East peace groups, 1984-1997, and undated
  - Miscellaneous communications and mailings, 1986,1999,and undated
  - Miscellaneous fliers and pamphlets, 1996 and undated
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1974-2003, (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - North American Coordinating Committee for NGOs on the Question of Palestine, 1996-1998
  - "Palestine and the UN"1997-1999, 2002
  - Physicians for Human Rights, 1996-1997
  - Tour and trip reports, 1983,1996
  - United Nations - Division for Palestinian Rights, 1995-1998
- Research Files, 1970-2003
  - AFL-CIO and foreign policy, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Council of Jewish Communities in Judea, Samara, and Gaza, 1985, 1990-1992
  - Israel Defense Forces - orders files, 1982-1989
  - Israel Defense Forces - prosecution files, 1987-1988
  - Israel foreign policy, 1984, undated
  - Israel - tourism, 1997
  - Israeli militarism, 1982
  - Jewish student activism, 1979, 1982
  - Labor party and Arabs, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Labor - pro-Israeli, 1988,1989,1992,undated
  - Labor rights - Generalized System of Preferences, 1988-1990, and undated, (2 folders)
  - Land, agriculture, settlements, 1978-1995
  - Lands and settlements, 1980-1991, (2 folders)
  - Lands and settlements-real estate brochures, 1991, undated
  - Lands and settlements-water, 1986,1987, undated
  - Left-wing publications and propaganda, 1970,1983,1993, undated
  - Palestine solidarity movement, 1984
  - Palestine trade and labor unions, 1988, and undated
  - PLO - Central Election Commission, 1996
  - PLO publications, 1989-1997
  - Progressive Student Network, 1981-1982
  - Pro-Israeli Christians, 1996-1997
  - Pro-Israeli publications, 1975-1983, undated
  - Research notes - justice system and taxation, undated
  - State of Israel - government publications, 1973,1988-2003
- Audio-Visual Materials,2006 and undated
  - 16 videocassettes, 4 DVDs, 1 CDROM, and 1 audiocassette on Israel and Palestine. Originals of video and audiotapes are closed to use. Patrons must request use copies to access the content of the material. (Box 10)
- Oversize Materials, 1982-2000, (2 oversize folders, 1 flat box)
  - Publications from B'Tselem, palestinian human rights organizations, and foreign-based solidarity groups, 1983-2006, (3 oversize folders) (Box 11)
  - 2 maps of occupation and dislocation of Palestinian settlements,1 map and welcome brochure for Russian emigres, 1982, 2000, 1989 (Opaperfolder OF-1)
  - Al-Haq political poster, 2004 (Opaperfolder OF-2)
  - Posters concerning human rights in the Isreal/Palestine conflict, political movements in Latin America, and film screenings and film festivals related to human rights, 1977-1997 and undated (Opaperfolder OF-3)
  - Larger posters concerning human rights in the Israel/Palestine conflict, 1999 and undated (Opaperfolder OF-4)
  - Newspapers quoting Marty, 1982-2007 (Opaperfolder OF-5)